Welcome, come back.
We've seen a lot of code you're seeing on
the screen right now, right?
A lot of stuff you've seen, a lot of strategies you've seen,
as I said before, you gotta have the clarity
of thought about what you wanna achieve.
And that clarity comes by going through the course,
doing the hands-on, asking the
right questions, getting more clarity.
We are in, in an era where attention
and focus is your biggest asset, okay?
With so much of distraction around so much of
new shiny things coming around every now and then,
and so much of information overload that is happening
with help of social media like LinkedIn or YouTube.
You, you go into LinkedIn, you get sucked over there, right?
You have people saying, okay, I, I cracked an interview.
I cracked, uh, four interviews, join another company.
And you go to YouTube, you get sucked to.
The point I'm trying to make here is that your attention,
if you really redirect towards your goals,
you'll make progress a lot, lot faster.
And I can tell you from my own personal experience,
f you know, I was at a stage
where I would just constantly consume
and then work, create, consume, create, consume, create.
There was a nonstop context switch happening in my brain.
And, uh, I wasn't really making any
meaningful progress as such, okay?
When I was driving, I would have the YouTube podcast on
when I was waiting in a grocery store.
When, when I was waiting for anything for that matter,
I would just take out my phone, look at LinkedIn,
look at WhatsApp, look at Gmail.
Essentially, I had lost the habit of thinking, you know,
which is extremely important.
You gotta be spending time with yourself.
That is when you actually get clarity about your goals,
your next steps as such.
And I got so fed up with my own habit
of getting distracted every now
and then that I got a few books for me
to really overcome this issue.
And I'll, I highly recommend three books.
And they are here, in fact,
in just get them to you for you right now.
If you look at, uh, this book here, one
of the best books ever, okay?
Atomic Habits. And this one is also extremely good, uh,
indestructible, uh, practical tips on how can actually, um,
you know, a wide, a lot of noise that we have in our head
and, uh, because of social media
and other applications in fact.
And, uh, lastly, this, this book was a game changer for me.
Game changer, amazing book.
The first 40% of the book is very, very difficult to read.
The next 60% is mind blowing, mind blowing.
So you got to have patience with this book.
First 40% is difficult to understand.
The words are not easy, but this next 60% is
simply mind boggling.
And trust me, those three books have really helped me a lot.
So I would highly recommend you spend at least 30 minutes a
day, uh, over the bit of next, uh, you know, two,
three months, and you will see your life transforming.
Okay? Now, back to the topic.
Uh, what you need to really know, apart from the clarity
of thought is that
You should be able to at least write
this pseudo code, okay?
And says pseudo code, it's about,
what you see here is a code, right?
Pseudo code is in plain English words.
Essentially, you know, what do you wanna do?
Or read a file next, uh, filter this file next,
transform this file, do some aggregations.
Next, uh, join this file, uh, with another file. Okay?
And then finally, load this file back into university.
There is a pseudo code.
So you gotta have this much clarity for you to be able
to achieve building of a data pipeline that is,
that is going be far, far better than
what a human can write.
Okay? Now, as far as clarity is concerned,
I will be letting you about a lot of different things.
Uh, as the course progresses, you will get clarity.
So make sure you not only finish this course,
but there are some courses coming up ahead as well i,
in the path that I've laid out.
So make sure you go through them.
Extremely important where you will get a lot more clarity
about the different concepts in data engineering.
Okay? Now, back to a project. So what have you done so far?
We have, um, you know, built three jobs, right?
Job one, job two, and job three.
One gets data from, uh, NYC
loads into, uh, raw.
And, uh, the second job actually reads some raw
and loads into, uh, curated.
And third one, um, reads from curated
and loads into the aggregated layer.
And we saw how we can incrementally load it as well, right?
So that, that is all something which is done right now.
Now we need to automate this. Now one has to run,
then the second one has to run,
then the third one has to run.
Okay, if at all, the first one fails.
Uh, second and third should not run if at all.
Second one fails, third should not run.
And if at all, any one of them fails, somebody has
to get notified, right?
So that they can look into it.
And typically we have support teams who looks into the jobs
that fail in production environment.
We are now in development. We are, we'll ultimately go
to production, right when the jobs run every single day.
And in production environment, we have a support team
who looks into the failures.
And for them to look ference, they have to be notified.
So we need to achieve that part as well.
So we'll look at two services in this particular section,
uh, a section dedicated to SNS
and step function.
Okay? SNS is called, uh,
or used to send emails to the support teams.
And step functions are used for orchestrating.
The word is orchestrating, you know, you
or on the jobs sequentially in our use case.
And, uh, other use case would be that,
let's say the jobs really finish, all of them really finish
and data is available in aggregated layer.
You'd also want to inform the data analyst
team data has been loaded.
Go take a look, maybe run a report.
That also can be done with the OSNS.
Essentially, you can send an email to anybody you want to.
Okay? So let's, uh, take a look at SNS, uh,
in the next video.